<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technical guide on LoopedLine</title>
    <link>https://loopedline.com/tags/technical-guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technical guide on LoopedLine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 12:52:47 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopedline.com/tags/technical-guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Git</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-started-with-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 12:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-started-with-git/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is part of a series about Git and GitHub.
In the previous post we looked at what Git and GitHub are, what problems they solve, and some key differences between them.
The goal of this post is to get you started working with Git as simply as possible.
To keep things simple we&amp;rsquo;ll narrow our focus in this post in three ways:
  We&amp;rsquo;ll look at just Git - not GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Introduced to Git and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-introduced-to-git-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 14:25:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-introduced-to-git-and-github/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is part of a series about Git and GitHub.
Git and GitHub are two related but separate tools that are helpful for software development, as well as many other things.
They are both flexible and powerful, which makes them very useful.
But that flexibility and power come from some complex features and interactions that can also make them seem intimidating at first. They do not need to be intimitidating, however.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git and GitHub - Topic</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/git-and-github-topic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 13:40:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/git-and-github-topic/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is the start of a series on Git and GitHub.
There are many uses for Git and GitHub so there&amp;rsquo;s isn&amp;rsquo;t one right path for learning about them. Some users will utilize one set of features, while another group of users may focus on a fairly different set of features. Consequently, an efficient path for learning about Git and GitHub will depend on what you want to do with those tools and how you intend to use them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Your First Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/building-your-first-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 21:05:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/building-your-first-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>Who this is for If you want to build your first website with Hugo, this article is meant to get you started.
It is not an exhaustive or extensive guide. There are other good resources for that, and several are linked below.
But here you&amp;rsquo;ll find instructions on the critical path to get a website up and working.
There&amp;rsquo;s magic in motion, and just getting started is often the most important thing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>