<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo theme on LoopedLine</title>
    <link>https://loopedline.com/tags/hugo-theme/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo theme on LoopedLine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 20:52:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopedline.com/tags/hugo-theme/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Including Last Modified Date in Hugo Posts</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/including-last-modified-date-in-hugo-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 20:52:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/including-last-modified-date-in-hugo-posts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
This post is part of an ongoing effort to tailor the theme over time.
Objective In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll add a last modified date to posts in Hugo.
We already have a date field that reflects when a post was first published. We want to keep that date and conditionally add a new date that reflects when the post was last updated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Improved List Page Navigation for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/building-improved-list-page-navigation-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 20:25:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/building-improved-list-page-navigation-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
This post is part of an ongoing effort to tailor the theme over time.
Objective In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll build a new user interface for navigating between list pages.
As of this writing, the list page has right and left arrows that allow navigating to the list pages for earlier and later posts. We&amp;rsquo;ll keep those, and add a count of the list pages to provide some context, as well as adding a link to the All Posts list page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Building a List of All Posts in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/automatically-building-a-list-of-all-posts-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 14:29:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/automatically-building-a-list-of-all-posts-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>The Challenge This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
This post is part of an ongoing effort to tailor the theme over time.
For this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how to build an automated list of all posts in the /project/content/post/ directory while leaving the existing paginator unaltered.
Hugo allows one list template per section, and since we want to keep the existing paginator, we need to find another way to automatically build that list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing a Hugo Theme Over Time</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/changing-a-hugo-theme-over-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 14:17:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/changing-a-hugo-theme-over-time/</guid>
      <description>Background This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
Consequently, nearly all design choices were initially made by the theme&amp;rsquo;s creator.
Naturally, when selecting a theme, you choose the one that best meets your goals. And the Minimal theme was chosen because it is clean and well-written.
But no theme is likely to match your project&amp;rsquo;s needs in every detail. As Zachary Wade Betz puts it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the Spacing of Font Awesome Icons in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/changing-the-spacing-of-font-awesome-icons-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 13:54:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/changing-the-spacing-of-font-awesome-icons-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>The Problem This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
This post is part of an ongoing effort to tailor the theme over time.
In this post, after resolving the problem of Changing the Size of Font Awesome Icons in Hugo, we now want to increase the spacing between the arrow icons used for page navigation icons on list pages.
The Process From the previous investigation mentioned above we know that the arrow icons are defined in the fa-arrow-left and fa-arrow-right elements of the paginator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the Size of Font Awesome Icons in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/changing-the-size-of-font-awesome-icons-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 14:36:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/changing-the-size-of-font-awesome-icons-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>The Problem This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
This post is part of an ongoing effort to tailor the theme over time.
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at changing the page navigation icons on list pages. For our purposes, the arrows used at the bottom of each list page are too small, making them difficult to click.
The Process As has been mentioned before, because Hugo offers so much flexibility and produces pages in such a layered way, it can be difficult to find the right place to make the necessary alterations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modifying the New Article Template in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/modifying-the-new-article-template-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 14:12:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/modifying-the-new-article-template-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Background This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
This post is part of an ongoing effort to tailor the theme over time.
After working with Hugo for a while you might find that there are certain pieces of code that you include in every project.
Once you tire of manually copying and pasting them, it&amp;rsquo;s time to figure out which template file to alter to automatically include those snippets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling Hugo&#39;s Automatic Hyperlinking of URLs [SOLVED]</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/disabling-hugos-automatic-hyperlinking-of-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 14:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/disabling-hugos-automatic-hyperlinking-of-urls/</guid>
      <description>The Problem This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
This post is part of an ongoing effort to tailor the theme over time.
For this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the issue that when Hugo rendered a webpage from a markdown file it automatically converted text URLs to hyperlinks.
The Process A web search for how to disable automatic hyperlinking in Hugo led to a few discussions of the issue:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>