<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual Studio Code on LoopedLine</title>
    <link>https://loopedline.com/tags/visual-studio-code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visual Studio Code on LoopedLine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 13:46:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://loopedline.com/tags/visual-studio-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Backing Up Visual Studio Code (VS Code) Settings and Extensions With a Bash Script</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/backing-up-vs-code-settings-and-extensions-with-a-bash-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 13:46:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/backing-up-vs-code-settings-and-extensions-with-a-bash-script/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is part of a series about automating data backups in Linux.
In the previous post we automated the process to backup a .bashrc file with a Bash script.
In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll automate the process of backing up Visual Studio Code (VS Code) settings and a list of installed extensions with a Bash script.
The Script We&amp;rsquo;ve developed Bash scripts for automating tasks in previous posts, so we&amp;rsquo;ll leverage that work and modify it for our current purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You (2022)</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/thank-you-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 11:24:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/thank-you-2022/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This project exists thanks to the incredible generosity of a tremendous number of people.
It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible to thank everyone who contributed. Acknowledgements are always incomplete.
Yet we want to make the attempt to express our gratitude.
Scope This project (in its current form) is now one year old.
We want to acknowledge the contributions of various companies, organizations, and groups that helped it reach this point.
While we might desire to be more granualar in our approbation, it would be both impractical in scope and imbalanced in outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Code Learning Path and Recommended Resources</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/vscode-learning-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 09:28:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/vscode-learning-path/</guid>
      <description>Learning Path for Visual Studio Code Step 1: Getting Started with Visual Studio Code Perhaps the best place to start learning about Visual Studio Code is the introduction to VS Code by James Q Quick. It also provides an introduction to Visual Studio Code Extensions as well as Emmet.
Then to get a refresher and a slightly different view, watch Getting started with Visual Studio Code and Get started with VS Code Extensions by the VS Code team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
