<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Font Awesome on LoopedLine</title>
    <link>https://loopedline.com/tags/font-awesome/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Font Awesome on LoopedLine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 11:24:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopedline.com/tags/font-awesome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You (2022)</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/thank-you-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 11:24:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/thank-you-2022/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This project exists thanks to the incredible generosity of a tremendous number of people.
It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible to thank everyone who contributed. Acknowledgements are always incomplete.
Yet we want to make the attempt to express our gratitude.
Scope This project (in its current form) is now one year old.
We want to acknowledge the contributions of various companies, organizations, and groups that helped it reach this point.
While we might desire to be more granualar in our approbation, it would be both impractical in scope and imbalanced in outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Improved List Page Navigation for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/building-improved-list-page-navigation-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 20:25:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/building-improved-list-page-navigation-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Note of Caution The approach detailed in this post has some problems and produces confusing results for subsection list pages.
It was replaced and superceded by the approach used in this post.
Update Note When this post was originally published, it linked to a dynamic version of the All Posts list page. That page has been retired. Consequently, links to that page have been replaced with a links to a saved static version of that page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the Spacing of Font Awesome Icons in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/changing-the-spacing-of-font-awesome-icons-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 13:54:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/changing-the-spacing-of-font-awesome-icons-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>The Problem This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
This post is part of an ongoing effort to tailor the theme over time.
In this post, after resolving the problem of Changing the Size of Font Awesome Icons in Hugo, we now want to increase the spacing between the arrow icons used for page navigation icons on list pages.
The Process From the previous investigation mentioned above we know that the arrow icons are defined in the fa-arrow-left and fa-arrow-right elements of the paginator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the Size of Font Awesome Icons in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/changing-the-size-of-font-awesome-icons-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 14:36:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/changing-the-size-of-font-awesome-icons-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>The Problem This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
This post is part of an ongoing effort to tailor the theme over time.
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at changing the page navigation icons on list pages. For our purposes, the arrows used at the bottom of each list page are too small, making them difficult to click.
The Process As has been mentioned before, because Hugo offers so much flexibility and produces pages in such a layered way, it can be difficult to find the right place to make the necessary alterations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>