<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git on LoopedLine</title>
    <link>https://loopedline.com/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Git on LoopedLine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:42:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopedline.com/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Git Remote Repositories (Like GitHub)</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-started-with-git-remote-repositories-like-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:42:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-started-with-git-remote-repositories-like-github/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is part of a series about Git and GitHub.
In all our previous posts we worked with Git locally.
In this post we&amp;rsquo;re going to look at using Git to work with remote repositories.
What is a remote repository? According to the &amp;ldquo;Git Basics - Working with Remotes&amp;rdquo; section from Pro Git by Scott Chacon and Ben Straub:
 Remote repositories are versions of your project that are hosted on the Internet or network somewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Git Branching and Merging</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-started-with-git-branching-and-merging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 09:00:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-started-with-git-branching-and-merging/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is part of a series about Git and GitHub.
In the previous post we looked at how to start working with Git as simply as possible. We did that by focusing on only Git, working with it only locally, and using only the most basic commands.
After installing and setting up Git, the commands we looked at were those for establishing a Git repository and completing the Version Control Cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Git</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-started-with-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 12:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-started-with-git/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is part of a series about Git and GitHub.
In the previous post we looked at what Git and GitHub are, what problems they solve, and some key differences between them.
The goal of this post is to get you started working with Git as simply as possible.
To keep things simple we&amp;rsquo;ll narrow our focus in this post in three ways:
  We&amp;rsquo;ll look at just Git - not GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Introduced to Git and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-introduced-to-git-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 14:25:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/getting-introduced-to-git-and-github/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is part of a series about Git and GitHub.
Git and GitHub are two related but separate tools that are helpful for software development, as well as many other things.
They are both flexible and powerful, which makes them very useful.
But that flexibility and power come from some complex features and interactions that can also make them seem intimidating at first. They do not need to be intimitidating, however.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git and GitHub - Topic</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/git-and-github-topic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 13:40:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/git-and-github-topic/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is the start of a series on Git and GitHub.
There are many uses for Git and GitHub so there&amp;rsquo;s isn&amp;rsquo;t one right path for learning about them. Some users will utilize one set of features, while another group of users may focus on a fairly different set of features. Consequently, an efficient path for learning about Git and GitHub will depend on what you want to do with those tools and how you intend to use them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>