<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GitHub Pages on LoopedLine</title>
    <link>https://loopedline.com/tags/github-pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GitHub Pages on LoopedLine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 11:24:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopedline.com/tags/github-pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You (2022)</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/thank-you-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 11:24:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/thank-you-2022/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This project exists thanks to the incredible generosity of a tremendous number of people.
It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible to thank everyone who contributed. Acknowledgements are always incomplete.
Yet we want to make the attempt to express our gratitude.
Scope This project (in its current form) is now one year old.
We want to acknowledge the contributions of various companies, organizations, and groups that helped it reach this point.
While we might desire to be more granualar in our approbation, it would be both impractical in scope and imbalanced in outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Website Subdomain to Host Content With Different Providers</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/setting-up-a-website-subdomain-to-host-content-with-different-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 13:15:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/setting-up-a-website-subdomain-to-host-content-with-different-providers/</guid>
      <description>Background This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
This post is part of an ongoing effort to tailor the theme over time.
Specifically, this post is part of a project to build a contact form with Hugo and host it with Netlify.
Objective In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll setup a subdomain for our website so that we can easily host content with two different hosting providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project - Building a Contact Form With Hugo and Hosting it with Netlify</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/project-building-a-contact-form-with-hugo-and-hosting-it-with-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 12:18:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/project-building-a-contact-form-with-hugo-and-hosting-it-with-netlify/</guid>
      <description>Background This project is built with Hugo and uses the Minimal Hugo theme.
This post is part of an ongoing effort to tailor the theme over time.
Specifically, this is the first post for a project to build a contact form with Hugo and host it with Netlify.
Objective In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll outline the overall approach for the project.
There are many ways to accomplish this task offering various tradeoffs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>