<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shell on LoopedLine</title>
    <link>https://loopedline.com/tags/shell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in shell on LoopedLine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 11:37:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopedline.com/tags/shell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using sed in a Bash Script to Update Hugo Front Matter</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/using-sed-in-bash-script-to-update-hugo-front-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 11:37:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/using-sed-in-bash-script-to-update-hugo-front-matter/</guid>
      <description>Background Hugo used to have an undraft command to quickly alter front matter before publishing, but it was removed.
The command would update &amp;ldquo;the content’s draft status from ‘True’ to ‘False’ and&amp;hellip; the date to the current date and time&amp;rdquo;.
That&amp;rsquo;s useful functionality, so we&amp;rsquo;ll replicate it with a Bash script.
For this project we&amp;rsquo;ll use sed, which is one of the basic programs that comes with most distributions of Linux and it&amp;rsquo;s useful for (among other things) replacing segments of text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the $RANDOM Variable in Bash</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/random-variable-in-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 15:48:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/random-variable-in-bash/</guid>
      <description>Creating Randomness in Bash There are many shell variables used in Bash. One of them is the Bash variable $RANDOM.
$RANDOM returns a pseudo-random number between 0 and 32767.
Try it by typing the following command into a Bash command line interpreter:
echo $RANDOM Run the command multiple times to see different results.
Changing the possible return range We can reduce the range of the output by using the modulo operator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s a Difference Between rename and rename.ul in Bash</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/difference-between-rename-and-rename.ul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 13:20:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/difference-between-rename-and-rename.ul/</guid>
      <description>Confusion with rename There are several software packages with the name &amp;ldquo;rename&amp;rdquo; available for Bash.
That can cause confusion if you&amp;rsquo;re not aware of the fact.
Adding to the confusion, on many distributions of Linux, like Debian and Ubuntu, the rename command doesn&amp;rsquo;t refer to the &amp;ldquo;rename&amp;rdquo; that is part of the util-linux package. Instead, it likely refers to a &amp;ldquo;perl-rename&amp;rdquo; package. To call the util-linux version you&amp;rsquo;ll likely have to use the rename.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash - Getting Started Working with the Shell</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/bash-getting-started-working-with-the-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 17:12:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/bash-getting-started-working-with-the-shell/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Bash When you think of someone expertly working with a computer you might picture them stereotypically entering commands on a black screen with green text, the computer responding with rapidly scrolling walls of characters.
For a long time I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize the thing they were typing in was called a shell. (The differences between a terminal, console, command line, and shell are nuanced. Many of the responses to this StackExchange question offer some helpful insight and perspective on the topic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>