<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technical troubleshooting - solved on LoopedLine</title>
    <link>https://loopedline.com/tags/technical-troubleshooting-solved/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technical troubleshooting - solved on LoopedLine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 23:14:22 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopedline.com/tags/technical-troubleshooting-solved/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Escaping Markdown Code Fences Within Code Fences [SOLVED]</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/escaping-markdown-code-fences-within-code-fences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 23:14:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/escaping-markdown-code-fences-within-code-fences/</guid>
      <description>The Problem When authoring articles using Markdown that include Markdown special characters in the content, questions can come up about how to escape those special characters.
For instance, this article about updating Hugo posts with code syntax highlighting includes Markdown code fences within code fences, which required figuring out how to escape code fences within code fences.
The Process A web search quickly led to this helpful article, which explained the options for escaping code fencing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Hugo Posts with Code Syntax Highlighting [SOLVED]</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/updating-hugo-posts-with-code-syntax-highlighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 15:07:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/updating-hugo-posts-with-code-syntax-highlighting/</guid>
      <description>The Problem Hugo&amp;rsquo;s code fence syntax produced code blocks but didn&amp;rsquo;t produce code with syntax highlighting.
The Process A web search for syntax highlighting in Hugo returned some Hugo documentation pages:
 Syntax Highlighting Configure Markup: Highlight  While these offered some background information, they didn&amp;rsquo;t help resolve the issue.
 That search also returned this article, which provided an example for one solution of adding the following to the Hugo config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apt Update Not Working on Windows Subsystem for Linux [SOLVED]</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/apt-update-not-working-on-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 15:20:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/apt-update-not-working-on-wsl/</guid>
      <description>The Problem In Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) when running the command
sudo apt update the following error appears for every package
 &amp;ldquo;Temporary failure resolving &amp;lsquo;archive.ubuntu.com&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;
 and nothing is updated.
Furthermore, nothing can be installed using the command
sudo apt install &amp;lt;&amp;lt;PACKAGE-NAME&amp;gt;&amp;gt; for the same reason.
The Process A web search for the error led to a StackExchange question discussing the issue, which offered guidance on the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to Open the Bash Shell in Ubuntu via Windows Subsystem for Linux [SOLVED]</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/unable-to-open-bash-on-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 13:15:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/unable-to-open-bash-on-wsl/</guid>
      <description>The Problem When attempting to open the Bash shell in Ubuntu via Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) on Windows Terminal only the following message appears:
 The Windows Subsystem for Linux instance has terminated.
[process exited with code &amp;hellip;]
 The Process Part of the resolution process and sources are lost to me now, but I still want to document the solution that seems to resolve the issue.
A key seems to be running the terminal instance as administrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabling Hugo&#39;s Automatic Hyperlinking of URLs [SOLVED]</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/disabling-hugos-automatic-hyperlinking-of-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 14:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/disabling-hugos-automatic-hyperlinking-of-urls/</guid>
      <description>The Problem When Hugo rendered a webpage from a markdown file it automatically converted text URLs to hyperlinks.
The Process A web search for how to disable automatic hyperlinking in Hugo led to a few discussions of the issue:
 Disabling smart quotes, auto code blocks, and auto hyperlinks? Goldmark: How to disable autolinks Configure Markup: Goldmark  Interpolating between them led to a solution.
The Solution Adding the following to the config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Site Looks Different Served Locally vs Remotely [SOLVED]</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/hugo-site-looks-different-served-locally-vs-remotely/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 22:44:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/hugo-site-looks-different-served-locally-vs-remotely/</guid>
      <description>The Problem When a new website layout generated with Hugo was pushed to production it rendered very differently on the web than it appeared locally.
It looked like the CSS was only partially applied and some elements overlapped one another.
The Process First, the source files were compared, but, as expected, they appeared identical.
Next, DevTools in the Chrome browser was used to compare a sample element on the site running locally vs remotely and showed that the sites were being styled by different CSS rules.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>