<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>regular expressions on LoopedLine</title>
    <link>https://loopedline.com/tags/regular-expressions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in regular expressions on LoopedLine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 21:21:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopedline.com/tags/regular-expressions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Renaming Files with the rename Command (the Perl Version)</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/renaming-files-with-rename-command-the-perl-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 21:21:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/renaming-files-with-rename-command-the-perl-version/</guid>
      <description>Renaming files with the rename command Renaming files is a basic and mundane task.
Fortunately, there are several tools to make it easier.
The Perl version of rename available in Bash on many Linux distributions is especially powerful since it can utilize regular expressions.
Confirm which version(s) of rename you have available As previously mentioned there can be more than one version of the rename command on your system. So you&amp;rsquo;ll first want to confirm that you have the Perl version of rename installed and verify how the command is invoked on your system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s a Difference Between rename and rename.ul in Bash</title>
      <link>https://loopedline.com/post/difference-between-rename-and-rename.ul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 13:20:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopedline.com/post/difference-between-rename-and-rename.ul/</guid>
      <description>Confusion with rename There are several software packages with the name &amp;ldquo;rename&amp;rdquo; available for Bash.
That can cause confusion if you&amp;rsquo;re not aware of the fact.
Adding to the confusion, on many distributions of Linux, like Debian and Ubuntu, the rename command doesn&amp;rsquo;t refer to the &amp;ldquo;rename&amp;rdquo; that is part of the util-linux package. Instead, it likely refers to a &amp;ldquo;perl-rename&amp;rdquo; package. To call the util-linux version you&amp;rsquo;ll likely have to use the rename.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>